<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Dr Michael Noetel</title>
    <link>https://noetel.com.au/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Dr Michael Noetel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 19:53:42 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noetel.com.au/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>INSPIRE</title>
      <link>https://noetel.com.au/projects/inspire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noetel.com.au/projects/inspire/</guid>
      <description>INSPIRE is about knowledge translation for university teaching. How do we take the best evidence on what works for teaching and learning so we can apply it in practice?
Why and how of INSPIRE As a teacher at a university, there are hundreds of little decisions that add up to a radically different student experience. You need to choose learning objectives, choose assessments, choose learning activities, and choose how to present content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Altruism 3</title>
      <link>https://noetel.com.au/projects/effective_altruism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 19:44:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noetel.com.au/projects/effective_altruism/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in questions that focus on impartially improving welfare. I am increasingly focused on research that is important, neglected, and tractable, with a long-term view of the future.
EA Activities   A founding member of READI Research which created project including
  What works to increase charitable donations? A meta-review with meta-meta-analysis
  Interventions that Influence Animal-Product Consumption: A Meta-Review
  Survey of COVID-19 Responses to Understand Behaviour (SCRUB) and derivative papers (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematic Reviews</title>
      <link>https://noetel.com.au/projects/systematic_reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:50:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noetel.com.au/projects/systematic_reviews/</guid>
      <description>Systematic reviews are the core of evidence-informed decision-making. I&amp;rsquo;ve developed expertise in all parts of conducting a range of systematic reviews, meta-analyses, and meta-reviews (a.k.a., overviews of reviews).
Publications  Video Improves Learning In Higher Education: A Systematic Review. Review of Educational Research. Impact Factor: 8.241 School-Based Interventions Modestly Increase Physical Activity And Cardiorespiratory Fitness But Are Least Effective For Youth Who Need Them Most: An Individual Participant Pooled Analysis of 20 Controlled Trials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Translation</title>
      <link>https://noetel.com.au/projects/knowledge_translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 19:53:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noetel.com.au/projects/knowledge_translation/</guid>
      <description>I think there&amp;rsquo;s so much wisdom trapped in universities. Often, getting that knowledge out into practice can save lives.
&amp;lt;embed STUDIO video&amp;gt;
This is a pitch I made to our university in 2021 for why I think knowledge translation is so important
Many of my projects have been about translating academic knowledge into practice. By using my skills in online learning, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to help those projects have impact cost-effectively and at scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video and Multimedia</title>
      <link>https://noetel.com.au/projects/video_multimedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:56:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noetel.com.au/projects/video_multimedia/</guid>
      <description>Why video is great
How i know
What I&amp;rsquo;ve done
Photo by Jakob Rosen on Unsplash</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Thesis</title>
      <link>https://noetel.com.au/projects/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://noetel.com.au/projects/thesis/</guid>
      <description>My thesis looked at the effects of mindfulness in sport and performance settings. It included:
 a systematic review of studies that explore mindfulness in athletes; machine learning methods for making short questionnaires, with a mindfulness case study; and a double-blinded randomised experiment that tested a brief mindfulness induction in athletes  Ultimately, I think the key lessons were that mindfulness isn&amp;rsquo;t the panacea that many make it out to be.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
